# LASZLO NEMETH



Prague, Czechia



nemeth0220@gmail.com



+420 792 588 205



lac0220.github.io/lac0220/



github.com/lac0220



gitlab.com/lac0220





linkedin.com/in/nemeth0220

#### **Professional Profile**

**Multilingual professional** with several years of experience in financial services and software development is eager to gain additional skills in the field of IT. **Service-focused** individual with a passion for UI design and enjoyable UX. **Detail-oriented** and **analytical mind** with a practical approach to problem-solving in a resourceful manner. **Well-organised team player** who is able to take the lead in achieving a certain objective on time and with excellence.



#### Skills



HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap 5, Git React.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, Gulp.js REST APIs, SQL, MySQL, VSC, Jira, Asana Hungarian – native speaker

German – full professional proficiency

English – full professional proficiency

## **Work History**

02/2023 – present

Clearstream Operations Prague s.r.o. (Prague, CZ)
Business Test Specialist

- Analysing requirements contained in specific User Stories and identifying business needs of clients in collateral management services
- Creating and executing test scenarios in a **Business Acceptance Testing** environment with an agile methodology approach
- Performing test evidence documentation and reporting bugs via Jira
- Communicating frequently with the Product Management and Operational teams
- Supporting the Global Securities Financing operation unit with BAU tasks

05/2022 - 01/2023

Marketup s.r.o. (Prague, CZ)
Junior Front-End Developer (Internship)

• Created and maintained front-end code in **React.js** and **TypeScript** 

I agree to the processing of personal data provided in this document for realising the recruitment process pursuant to the Personal Data Protection Act of 10 May 2018 (Journal of Laws 2018, item 1000) and in agreement with Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation)

- Customized user-facing components with **MUI library** to meet operational needs
- Adjusted proper visual hierarchy and alignment to optimize UI design
- Replaced CSS with SCSS for advanced features
- Assisted and cooperated with software development team on GitLab and Asana

05/2017 - 07/2022

NeoTax s.r.o. / Dendax International LLC (Prague, CZ)

Tax Process Manager / Project Manager / Tax Process Assistant

- Established and supervised the workflow of the tax processing team
- Analyzed and remodelled processing practices for changing business needs
- Implemented new automated tax services in cooperation with the IT team
- Performed User Acceptance Testing and reported defects via Jira
- Reviewed web content to improve search engine optimization (SEO)

07/2016 - 05/2017

PayPal Europe Services Ltd. (Dublin, IE)

**German Collections Specialist** 

• Monitored the status of negative accounts and obtained payments via phone

08/2015 - 06/2016

**Hewlett Packard Enterprise (Leixlip, IE)** 

**German Technical Support Analyst** 

- Provided first-line technical support with problem research and analytical troubleshooting on the full range of products and applications
- Monitored ticket queues and handled tickets on time
- Liaised with various service-level departments and escalated tickets for validation

## **Education**

09/2021 - 11/2021

Full-Stack Web Development course (12 weeks full-time Coding Bootcamp)

Tech Stack

HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js, Git, PHP, SQL, Laravel

Data4You z.s. (Prague, CZ)

09/2006 - 07/2011

B.A. and M.A. in International Relations

University of Pannonia (Veszprém, HU)

### **Interests**

Discovering more and more about web development technologies and techniques

Reading (history, philosophy)

Chess

Learning foreign languages (currently Russian)

## References

Name Kateřina Kafkova Petr Jandal

Company Marketup s.r.o. NeoTax s.r.o. / Dendax International LLC

Position Project Manager Managing Partner / Head of Development

Email katerina.kafkova@marketup.cz jandalpetr@gmail.com

Phone +420 605 839 667 +420 777 034 408